<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019 on Pi Society</title>
    <link>/tags/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019 on Pi Society</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>External Speaker: Thomas Mangin</title>
      <link>/news/2019/thomas-mangin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019/thomas-mangin/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered how the internet works? What sort of technology goes into connecting the world?
Where did it all come from, and who invented it?
And just how exactly do all of those cat pictures end up online?
PiSoc is very proud to introduce our first external speaker of the year - Thomas Mangin. Thomas is the Operational and Technical Director at Exa Networks, and has been since he co-founded the company in 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PiSoc Presents: Project Management</title>
      <link>/news/2019/project-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019/project-management/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get organised, PiSoc! We&amp;rsquo;ll soon be running our next PiSoc Presents - this time we&amp;rsquo;ll be teaching you about project management and organisation.
Our talk will take place on Monday 11th November, starting at 18:45. We&amp;rsquo;ll be teaching you the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; of Git, Git repository hosts (Github/Gitlab), and Trello.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t already use these tools and services, your projects will greatly benefit from them. They&amp;rsquo;re great for keeping your work organised - as well as displaying it online after the fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux 101 Recap</title>
      <link>/news/2019/linux-101-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019/linux-101-recap/</guid>
      <description>Penguin time was fun! Last week, we had a special PiSoc weekly meeting - our very first PiSoc Presents! Our Social Exec, Tom Mitchell, gave a lecture on &amp;ldquo;an introduction to Linux&amp;rdquo;. The talk covered what we mean by &amp;ldquo;Linux as a kernel&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;as an OS&amp;rdquo;, and the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; of Linux-based operating systems.
Incase you missed it, you can view/download the slides here.
We hope you all learned something and enjoyed the free pizza!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux 101 and Install Party 2019</title>
      <link>/news/2019/linux-101-and-install-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019/linux-101-and-install-party/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s penguin time, PiSoc! On 21/10/19 (at the time of writing, the coming Monday), we&amp;rsquo;ll be holding our first PiSoc presents lecture, as well as this semester&amp;rsquo;s Linux Install Party.
PiSoc Presents: Linux 101 Are you interested in Linux, but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start?
Does the command line confuse you?
Do you want to learn some things and eat free (as in free pizza) pizza?
Starting from 18:15, we&amp;rsquo;ll be delivering a lecture on the fundamentals of Linux-based operating systems, how they work and how to use them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshers&#39; Week 2019 recap</title>
      <link>/news/2019/freshers-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019/freshers-recap/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy week. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a awful lot of fun running events for the past week. If you missed out (and we&amp;rsquo;re really sorry if you did!), here&amp;rsquo;s a brief recap of what went on.
Tuesday: Computer Science Induction talks You may have seen our president, Chris Delee, give an &amp;ldquo;intro to PiSoc&amp;rdquo; talk at the induction day event. It covered who we are, what we do, and where you can find us if you want to get involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome, 2019 Freshers</title>
      <link>/news/2019/welcome-freshers-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019/welcome-freshers-2019/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, freshers of 2019! If you&amp;rsquo;ve not already been introduced, we&amp;rsquo;re Pi Society, but you can call us PiSoc. Our focus is on computer science (and occasionally maths and electrical engineering). We&amp;rsquo;re a motley crew of hackers, makers, technologists, and nerds.
We&amp;rsquo;ve got a load of interesting events on the horizon. Part of the roadmap for this year is as follows:
 A trip to Bletchley Park - the birthplace of British computer science A trip to an as-of-yet-undecided destination to be chosen by you, the members of PiSoc Talks from Rik Ferguson, Richard Hopkins, and Holly Grace Williams Society projects - the university has greenlit us building them a magic mirror for public display An AI hackathon in partnership with AI Gaming Linux install parties - we&amp;rsquo;ll help you Linux-ify your laptop (there&amp;rsquo;ll be free pizza, too) Gameathons - play video games to win prizes Weekly meetings and socials  We also get up to fun nerdy shenanigans like reversing bluetooth-powered kids toys, developing Telegram bots when we&amp;rsquo;re at the pub, or building terrible robots out of microcontrollers, hot glue and cardboard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>